(♪♪♪)
(POLICE SIRENS WAILING)
(INDISTINCT
POLICE RADIO CHATTER)
WOMAN 1: (VOICEOVER)
These streets
are like a dark soul.
These streets are like
the Kingdom of Heaven
to Gargos.
It's like an entity.
You know,
it consumes everything.
And it will either kill you,
or it'll make you stronger.
-(THUG GRUNTS)
-(MAN GROANS)
WOMAN 1: (VOICEOVER)
But you fucked up, sweetheart.
(THUG GRUNTS)
(WOMAN CLEARS THROAT)
(SPITS)
(MAN PANTING)
There are laws written
for these streets.
There is only one man
running this show.
Who the fuck do you
think you are, Detective Cortez?
(CANE TAPPING)
So, how's my favorite
motherfucker doin', hmm?
(PANTS)
Let me ask you somethin',
you still fuckin' that fat,
ugly redhead?
Fuck you. That's my wife.
Don't touch her!
What'd you say?
(COUGHS)
Listen, I know you talk
to everybody like that,
but I'm not everybody, okay?
Nice knowin' you.
(CORTEZ PANTING)
(NECK CRACKING)
(♪♪♪)
Hate to break this to you,
little piggy,
but there's only devils
in this kingdom of heaven.
I'll see you in hell.
Yeah.
You tell them Glenn Gargos
sent you.
(CORTEZ GROANS)
(THUG YELLING, CORTEZ GROANING)
(♪♪♪)
(CAR ENGINE WHIRRING)
(CAR DOORS OPEN AND SHUT)
Time's up, motherfucker.
The hell you think you're doing?
I told you shits
not to come back!
-(GUNSHOTS)
-Come on.
(MAN GROANING)
(SCREAMS)
What the fuck?
Renzo, smoke that bitch.
No, no, please.
(GUNSHOTS)
(♪♪♪)
MAN 1:
Renzo, what the fuck you doing?
Come on, come the fuck out!
Get the fuck out of here!
(♪♪♪)
♪ So this is life ♪
♪ At least for the moment ♪
♪ And isn't it somethin' ♪
♪ To reach for the stars ♪
♪ We wanna belong ♪
♪ We wanna be there ♪
♪ But here we are,
leaving the statues ♪
♪ We always left behind ♪
♪ And so worth nothin' ♪
♪ Least for nothin' ♪
♪ Give me somethin' a day
to take away ♪
♪ And all my needs ♪
♪ There's ways around ♪
♪ But you don't need to say it ♪
-♪ So this is life ♪
-(ALARM CLOCK BEEPING)
♪ It isn't leavin' ♪
♪ So I should probably
figure out ♪
♪ The kind of options
that are around me ♪
♪ And so, and I got
a lot of problems obviously ♪
♪ Just leave me alone,
give me a reason ♪
♪ Give me a sign ♪
♪ That it's all gonna be okay
again ♪
♪ Is that such a silly thing
to say within ♪
♪ And so I'm nothin' ♪
♪ Not for nothin' ♪
♪ Leave me somethin' a day
to take away ♪
♪ And we walked on the air ♪
♪ Like it was nothin' ♪
♪ Where's the fun in that game ♪
♪ She said ♪
♪ So this is life ♪
♪ I live it in the moment ♪
♪ But I don't know
if they were there ♪
♪ To turn me around ♪
♪ I wanna be loved ♪
♪ I wanna be patient ♪
♪ But there's nothing ♪
♪ That gives a good impression ♪
♪ She said ♪
♪ And it's fine ♪
♪ Maybe you ain't lyin' ♪
(PHONE KEYS BEEPING)
(CAR WHIRRING)
(PHONE RINGING)
Mornin', Jack.
Already checkin' up on me?
JACK:
Yes.
You're gonna
have to call me boss
every once in a while, you know?
Fuck you, too.
(CHUCKLES)
How's the house?
Colorful. Good thing I'm
up to date on my vaccines.
Look, I know the place has died,
but I want you
in the neighborhood.
Know the locals, customs,
all that shit.
(CLEARS THROAT)
Look, Jack, I still don't know
why you sent me here.
We've been through this once
or twice before, you know?
I'm not a grief counselor,
life coach,
or whatever you call
those quacks these days.
I do know
you're in the right place
for what you've been through.
Yeah.
Listen, I gotta run.
But watch yourself, Des.
You're gonna wanna move fast.
Do what you do best.
You hear me?
I hear you.
Oh, and Des, eat somethin'.
Stay sharp.
Jack, thanks.
(CHUCKLES)
Check out with me tomorrow.
Will do, boss man.
(CAR DOOR OPENS)
(GRUNTS)
♪ Maybe it's a sign ♪
♪ That there's a way
to make it through ♪
(DOOR BELL CHIMES)
(INDISTINCT LYRICS
IN BACKGROUND)
(SIGHS)
WAITRESS:
There you go. I think this is--
(INDISTINCT CONVERSATION)
(SIGHS)
Hi. Uh, what can I get you?
DES:
Uh...
What's good?
Uh, it's all good.
Okay.
What about this, uh,
Diablo here?
Uh, it's just a bacon, egg,
and cheese with some hot sauce.
-It's nothing fancy.
-(DOOR BELL CHIMES)
I'll give you a minute
to decide.
DES:
Sure, yeah.
What are you doing coming here
looking like this?
-Fuck's the matter with you?
-I just wanted...
If I have any money on me.
-Okay, I have $11.
-Thank you.
Get the fuck out of here.
(FOOTFALLS)
(DOOR CLOSES)
Uh, have you decided yet?
Just a coffee, black.
-Okay.
-Thanks.
Um, I know it's none
of my business,
but are you all right?
You're right,
it's none of your business.
Which I get.
But it just looked like you
might have been in a little bit
of trouble. Maybe I could help.
Yeah, right.
I'm Desmond Mitchell.
I just moved here from--
Only two reasons
someone like you moves here.
Either you're a cop
or you're a reporter.
Either way, I'm not interested
in talking to either.
I'm not a reporter.
Hmm.
(PHONE RINGS)
I'll go get you that coffee.
-Thanks.
-Yeah.
Uh...
Uh, you know what?
I'll take it to go.
Mitchell.
(♪♪♪)
Whoa, where do you think
you're going, boss?
Lieutenant Desmond Mitchell.
I was assigned to this district
by Chief Hager.
Oh, I guess that means
you are my boss.
Sorry about that.
Sergeant Davis,
you can call me Julie.
Come inside.
Cole.
Meet Lieutenant Mitchell.
He's, uh, from--
Where'd you say you were from?
I didn't. Oakland.
Oakland? Huh.
Well, this is Tom Cole,
our forensic analyst.
Sorry to drag you down
to this shit show,
your first day on the job.
Who's the Vic?
A guy named Lou Dobson.
People around here
called him Big Lou.
Damn shame.
He ran the store for 30 years.
Local legend.
Everyone loved him.
Not everyone.
He's got blood pooling off
the face and extremities.
I'd say he's been here
for a while.
Got 9-millimeter casings.
They're all over the place.
I'd say we're lookin'
at two shooters.
Who called it in?
Random customer, truck driver,
came in to get a coffee.
This is Lou's wife.
They ran the store together.
Looks like she was cleaning up
when she met her maker.
Anybody see anything?
Not likely.
(CLEARS THROAT)
Cash register was hit.
Looks like a typical robbery.
Security cameras?
The one behind the counter
is disabled.
Yeah, not the smartest idea,
considering the clientele.
But there's a second one
in the back
and we pulled the hard drive,
so we'll see what we can get.
All right, Sergeant.
Well, catch me up.
What do you think happened?
I think most likely
it's Red Flag.
Yeah, I had a briefin' on them.
DAVIS:
They run most of
the North Valley.
Lately, they started
to shake down local businesses
in Sun Valley and Chatsworth.
They tax the owners
for their protection,
but that's just horseplay.
Their real jam
is in the drug trade
and sex trafficking.
They smuggle, import.
I'd say they're 75% involved
in the distribution
of the Greater Los Angeles area.
(SIGHS)
You okay?
Yeah.
Let's just get this scene
processed.
All right. I'll meet you
back at the precinct.
You need a ride?
No, I'm good.
(DISTANT POLICE SIRENS)
(PHONE RINGING IN BACKGROUND)
Welcome to the asylum.
Robbery, narcotics,
gangs, homicide.
Like one big avalanche
of shit on this floor.
This is you.
Sorry, it's not much.
Had worse.
(CARTON THUDS)
What do you think of me
rounding up the troops
for a little meet-and-greet?
Great.
(KNOCKS)
(DOOR OPENS)
Okay, everyone.
I wanna introduce you
to Lieutenant Desmond Mitchell.
He was just reassigned here
from Oakland
to head our task force,
so play nice.
Floor's yours.
All right, let's start the dog
and pony show off
by introducing ourselves.
It's already in my file, man.
Humor me.
Start with you there, uh,
homegirl.
What?
I'm homegirl now
because I'm Latina?
You're homegirl
because you're feisty,
and that's what I'm lookin' for.
So stop bein' a pussy
and tell me your name
so we can get on
with our goddamn day.
Name's Mia Rodriguez.
Five years here in hell town.
Thank you, Mia.
You.
Dale Lewis, sir.
Sir.
Tell me something,
Lewis, you served?
Afghanistan, two tours.
DESMOND:
Marines?
Yes, sir.
Semper fi.
And you?
Shaye Wilson.
Was transferred here from
the West Hollywood Division.
That's quite a transfer.
What'd you do?
I fucked my
captain's brains out.
-Her wife didn't like it much.
-(CHUCKLES)
No, no. Can't imagine she did.
You already met
our Caltech whiz kid, Tom Cole.
All right. (CLEARS THROAT)
Let's cut through the red tape.
I'm here to replace
Lieutenant Cortez.
Being a special unit,
I'm sure you
were all very close,
and his death hit you hard.
So, yeah, my condolences.
But we are here to do a job,
and I don't have time to deal
with anyone's fuckin' feelings.
We're ready to work, sir.
Wow, you really are a lap dog,
Lewis.
Eat shit, Mia.
Hey, let's talk about
Cortez's murder.
All right?
I read the report.
Crime scene was clean.
No prints, no witnesses,
no suspects.
He was beaten
beyond recognition.
His body dumped near
the train tracks.
He had to be identified
by his dental records.
Yeah, that's just how shit
works around here, boss man.
The man don't play around.
The man.
Glenn Gargos,
known as Glenny G,
the so-called spearhead
of the Red Flag operation. Hmm?
Yeah, and the Red Flag
runs everything.
Not everything.
I was sent here to do a job,
and I intend to do it.
We're goin' after Red Flag,
and we're bringing the law
with us.
Yeah.
Nice to meet you, boss.
I give you two weeks.
To what? I quit?
Till you're dead.
Let's go.
(CLEARS THROAT)
It's a bunch of rays
of sunshine there.
Give it time.
Oh, I, uh, I got
the security footage linked up
if you wanna have a look.
DESMOND:
That's fast.
So the second camera actually
had a really good
depth of field.
Uh, it, uh, it had a really,
you know, good--
-Okay.
-Angle of the whole store.
-Right. Okay, let's go.
-Yeah, okay.
TOM:
Here come our robbers.
I'm running ballistics
on the casings.
Probably won't find anything,
but it's worth a shot.
You know most of the guns
on the streets,
they don't even have
serial numbers
by the time they get to us.
-Whoa, what's that?
-What's what?
There's a--
there was a movement there,
a shadow
behind the shelf right there.
Zoom in on that.
Well, look at that.
We have witnesses.
Okay, I wanna know who he is,
I wanna know where to find him.
Right. It's, you know,
it's gonna be hard
to use facial recognition.
That's pretty grainy.
But-- What's that?
Zoom in on that. Right there.
DAVIS:
I stand corrected.
We have two witnesses.
You're damn right, we do.
Okay, get Rodriguez
and Wilson on this, all right?
I want them canvassing
the neighborhood.
Just shake the tree,
see what drops.
On it.
Okay, if word gets out
that we got two witnesses
loose on the streets,
they're gonna be sittin' ducks.
I'm on it.
(DOOR BELL CHIMES)
(MAN LAUGHS)
What are you doing here?
Just came in to see
my beautiful sister.
(CHUCKLES)
You look like shit.
Why aren't you at work?
Chill, Ramos didn't need me
at the shop today.
Oh, so if I call down
there right now,
he's gonna tell me that?
What?
(MAN TAKING DEEP BREATHS)
You don't believe me?
No, I don't,
because your fucking broke ass
comes down here this morning,
and you clean me out,
and now you show up
here looking strung out as fuck.
What did you do with the cash
that I gave you?
(BANGS FIST ON TABLE)
I told you I get paid on Friday.
You have to put in the hours
to get paid, you dumbass.
What did you do with the cash?
I, uh...
(SIGHS)
MAN 2:
Uh...
You're unbelievable.
I'm so sick of this shit.
Rent is due and come Friday,
if you don't have your share,
I'm putting your ass
out on the street.
-Yeah.
-You got it?
Sit down.
I'll get you some food,
and then you go home
and sleep it off.
I hear you.
What?
(INDISTINCT LYRICS)
♪ Yeah, I'm crazy ♪
♪ Showin' you how to love ♪
(INDISTINCT LYRICS)
♪ And don't let it go ♪
MAN 1:
What's up, Raven?
The man wants to see you.
Both of you.
Damn girl, why are you
always so uptight?
'Cause the last time I covered
your ass with Gargos,
I ended up doing 24 hours
in county.
Why are you always
gonna bring up that shit?
Get the fuck away from my bar,
Chino.
And take your bitch with you.
♪ And I want you ♪
♪ Yeah, I want you to push ♪
♪ You're my style ♪
I told you what would happen
if that motherfucker
ever laid a hand on me again.
You didn't have to break my arm,
you fuckin' bitch!
Fuck you, Stubbs!
What's the body count
on the shipment?
Eight girls, 3K a head.
Although they're not gonna
be worth that to the high bidder
if this pencil dick can't keep
his hands off the product.
I barely laid a hand
on the girl.
She's lying!
Mm-hmm, tell me something,
Stubbs.
If we were to look at
your internet browser history,
would it conform
that you're more or less
of a piece of shit?
Enough!
Start the bidding
of the girls at 5K.
Round up the soldiers,
get some fresh meat.
I want them primed
for the next auction.
Whatever you say.
WOMAN 1:
Kayla, come here, come here.
Let's go get you a drink
at the bar with Raven.
And you and I can talk later,
okay?
-KAYLA: Yeah.
-Okay.
You've gotta be fuckin'
kidding me.
You, no, come with me.
Honey, not-- no.
Please, please, sweetheart,
not now.
Are you kidding me? Fuck.
CHINO:
What's up, Plenty G?
How you doin'?
(SIGHS)
What the hell is goin' on
with Big Lou?
A protection racket.
Why you guys think
you're fuckin' subcontractors
all of a sudden?
Hey, look,
this is a fucking business.
All you gotta do
is use your head, right?
It's business, plain and
simple.
That's it. That's all.
Damn straight, G.
GARGOS:
Hmm, look it--
Not for nothing,
but in this line of work,
there's always
gonna be repercussions.
Shit's always gonna go down.
We just gotta roll with it.
That's all.
I mean, why'd you let
the fuckin' witnesses go?
What? Wait a minute.
Wait, there was no witnesses
over there at all.
Uh, yes, you did.
Why the fuck are you
actually still standing here?
Can you guys leave? Please go.
Now. Duh-duh-duh.
So, Willie, who saw
what went down at the store?
Couple of nobodies.
One works
at the filling station.
The other one is gettin'
dealt with as we speak.
But we got bigger fish to fry.
We're on the streets.
So, there's a new cop planted
in the Major Crimes Division.
Some cowboy from Oakland.
Uh, it's all sorted out.
That's not gonna be a problem.
Okay.
(INDISTINCT LYRICS
IN BACKGROUND)
What? What is it?
Melinda wants to up the bid
to 5K a girl.
Well, that's more than
a 50% increase.
Clients aren't gonna be happy
about that.
Yeah, I know.
Oh, uh, what am I supposed
to tell them?
I don't know.
(KAYLA SIGHS)
I don't know how much longer
I can keep doing this, Rav?
-Hey.
-KAYLA: I can't.
Just look at me.
You know what Gargos will do
if we don't deliver.
So get your shit together.
(♪♪♪)
(CAR ENGINE WHIRRING)
(GROANING)
GANGBANGER 1:
Yo, where the sardines at, yo?
Give me the hard candy.
Yo, man, what the fuck?
You see this?
Oh, this motherfucker
really tryin' to play.
That's right, bitch.
Come on over here.
GANGBANGER 1:
Show him what time it is.
(GROANS)
GANGBANGER 1:
Shit.
(THUD)
Up my ass.
(THUMP)
(GANGBANGER GROANS)
-This fucker broke my nose!
-(GROANS)
-Hey, get the fuck over there.
-GANGBANGER 2: Cocksucker.
DESMOND:
Up against the wall. Now.
Let me see your hands.
I'm gonna say this one time,
and one time only.
I'm the law.
Things have changed.
So I don't wanna see you
two douchebags
out here on the streets unless
you're collecting donations
for the local church.
Do you understand?
Yes, yes, I understand!
Fuck, man.
What about you, curly fries,
you catch that?
I get it. Shit.
-LAPD, put your guns down!
-Wait!
COP:
Put your guns down!
Lieutenant Mitchell,
Special Unit Major Crimes.
Cuff these guys.
You, hands in the air!
Hands in the air!
Turn around.
Up against the wall.
Up against the wall!
Turn around.
Sign the affidavit
at the station.
Hey, you all right?
Man, get your crazy ass
away from me!
Man, fuck the law.
You're welcome.
Crazy white motherfucker
comin' up here
like he's Rambo and shit.
Name's Desmond.
Good for you.
What, you on medication
or something?
Not exactly. What's your name?
Why the fuck do you care?
Well, I'm new in town
and I'm lookin'
to make some friends.
(LAUGHING)
Oh, trust me.
You are gonna be real popular
around here.
(CLEARS THROAT)
I'm Olaf.
Olaf? What kinda name is that?
The name my mother gave to me.
You got a problem with it?
No. No.
You see a lot of things
around here, don't you, Olaf?
(SIGHS)
Yeah, more than I want to.
When was the last time
you ate something?
Come on.
So how long you been
on the streets?
Since I've been laid off
a job I worked for 25 years.
Figure those suits over there
on 5th
thought they could save
a buck by furloughing my ass
before I could retire.
You just couldn't stay away,
could you?
Well, I didn't get breakfast.
I see you brought a friend.
How you doin', Laura?
Hey, Olaf, I haven't seen
you around.
I was starting to get worried.
Ah, you know, nothin'
keeps me down for long.
So what can I get you guys?
Ah, burgers, fries,
coffees, please.
LAURA:
Got it, comin' right up.
Uh...
Hmm.
What?
What if I didn't want any
fuckin' burgers and fries?
(SIGHS)
What did you want, Olaf?
Yeah, burger and fries are fine.
You-- you just could have,
you know,
fuckin' asked about it.
Fair enough. Okay.
Look, you see a lot around here.
You see a lot than other
people don't.
You know the area,
you know the flow.
Yeah, so?
So I need a set of eyes
out there.
(LAUGHS)
Man, some cracker cop
buys me a cheeseburger
and some fried potatoes.
And now he thinks I'm some
kinda informant or some shit.
(OLAF CHUCKLES)
You just don't get it, do you?
You think you're the first
law man to come down here,
think he's gonna clean up
the town like John Wayne.
You do know what happened
to that last
righteous motherfucking
in your shoes.
Yeah, he's dead.
-(BANGS FIST ON TABLE)
-Damn right he is.
Which is what you're gonna be
if you don't slow the fuck down.
Okay. Okay.
So let me ask you this.
If you were in my shoes,
what would you do?
-Me?
-DESMOND: Hmm
(CHUCKLES)
I ain't in your shoes,
crazy ass fool.
DESMOND:
Whoa, whoa, whoa, where--
where you goin'?
Going to eat at the counter.
It's safer that way.
Uh, and thanks for the meal,
Jehovah Witness.
(OLAF GRUNTS)
(PHONE RINGS)
Mitchell.
All right, text me the location.
Have Davis
and the others meet me there.
Sorry, gotta run.
(♪♪♪)
What do we got?
Guy's name is Tim Tornes,
lives out here in the sticks.
Been workin' up
at the gas station up ahead
for a few years.
Kid went in a few minutes ago.
He looks nervous.
Anyone make contact yet?
Nope.
Just waitin' on your call,
Kemosabe.
Well, he's gonna get spooked
if we all go filin' in together.
So, we lose him,
he's in the wind,
we lose our only shot
at eyeballin' our shooters.
So what do you wanna do?
Stay back. All right, be ready.
Let me go see
if I can talk to him.
Let's keep this low key.
Yeah.
We'll just stay by the car.
(DOOR OPENS)
-(DOOR CLOSES)
-Tim Tornes?
Detective Mitchell.
(♪♪♪)
DESMOND:
Tim!
That's him, that's him!
DESMOND:
Tim, get down!
-(GUNSHOT)
-(GROANS)
(INDISTINCT LYRICS)
Son of a bitch.
(GUNSHOTS)
Hey! You okay?
You gotta keep pressure on it.
Keep pressure.
Go! Go!
♪ The things you used to see ♪
(INDISTINCT LYRICS)
♪ The things you
always believed ♪
(INDISTINCT LYRICS)
♪ The things you always wanted ♪
(GUNSHOTS)
The fuck.
♪ A change for good ♪
Fuck off!
Come on, get in here!
Get in the fuckin' ght!
(INDISTINCT LYRICS)
♪ Time is not on your side ♪
Oh, motherfucker.
Die! Come on, die, bitch!
(YELLING)
(GUNSHOTS)
♪ The clock kept ticking
since the day you realized ♪
♪ That something was missing,
this is no paradise ♪
♪ Are you gonna...
(INDISTINCT LYRICS) ♪
♪ Are you gonna hide ♪
♪ The clock kept ticking
since the day you realized ♪
♪ That something was missing,
this is no paradise ♪
(GUNSHOTS)
DESMOND:
Davis!
-Cover for me.
-WILSON: Okay, yeah, go.
♪ Are you gonna...
(INDISTINCT LYRICS) ♪
♪ Are you gonna hide ♪
So this is you keeping things
low key?
DESMOND:
Look...
Look, I've downed
a couple of them,
I think there's four left.
Tim's been shot.
He's gonna bust in here.
Cover me!
♪ A change for good ♪
(GUNSHOTS)
(GROANS)
♪ A change for good ♪
WILSON:
Go, go, go!
(GUNSHOTS)
-Hey, what are we doing?
-Get the fuck out of here!
Fucking go, man!
We gotta move!
(GUNSHOTS)
♪ Change your face,
and change your mind ♪
Let's go, come on!
♪ Change, change, change ♪
Drop it or I drop him!
Keys. Slowly.
(KEYS JINGLE)
DESMOND:
Slowly.
(KEYS CLATTER)
Get the fuck out of the car.
RODRIGUEZ:
I wanna see
everyone's fucking hands?
LEWIS:
Out of the car, now!
Hands, hands.
DESMOND:
In the back, get the fuck out!
Out!
Get on the fuckin' hood!
RENZO:
Relax.
RODRIGUEZ:
Bitch, shit the fuck up, man.
DESMOND:
Tailgate!
-(DOOR CLOSES)
-(OVERLAPPING CHATTER)
-Hands on the tailgate.
-Oh, shit, you fuckin' relaxed?
DESMOND:
Hands on the tailgate!
LEWIS:
Out of the car, now!
On the ground.
Spread off.
Other one!
Give me your other fuckin'...
Stupid idiot.
WILSON:
(INDISTINCT SPEECH)
DAVIS:
I called in a bus,
he'll be all right.
(PANTS)
You good?
How the fuck
did they find him so fast?
(♪♪♪)
(POLICE SIRENS WAILING
IN DISTANCE)
(OBJECT CLATTERS)
(KNOCKING ON DOOR)
Mitchell?
Um...
DAVIS:
You okay?
Yeah.
They're all being bag-tagged
or processed downstairs.
They, uh, found the kid.
The kid from
the surveillance footage?
What was left of him.
(GROANS)
Yo, yo, yo, yo, yo.
Please, stop, stop, please.
DAVIS:
Alexander, 16 years old.
ALEXANDER:
Please.
(ALEXANDER GROANS)
Thought you could get away, huh?
I won't say anything. Please.
Please, I won't tell anybody.
Yeah, you're right. You won't.
DAVIS:
Found near the same
set of tracks as Cortez.
It's like some kind of goddamn
dumping ground.
(SIGHS)
Hell of a first day.
Look, I was gonna
have some of the crew over
at my place
for some drinks tonight.
Figured we could talk some
things out, blow some steam.
It's gonna be hell of a lot
of paperwork over this.
You should come.
Yeah, thanks.
Great.
I'll text you the address.
(♪♪♪)
JACK:
Three dead bodies,
three in arrests,
public shooting gallery.
Don't waste any time, do you?
This is bullshit.
Have to be a little bit
more specific.
They were tipped off, Jack!
Only five people knew
there was witnesses
in the grocery mart robbery.
I go to pick one of them up,
and we're fuckin' ambushed!
Okay, the other witness
we're lookin' for, dead.
My crew are talkin'.
Okay? They're bent.
Somebody's payin' 'em off.
But you knew this, didn't you?
I have my suspicion, yeah.
You sent me into
the fuckin' lion's den.
You're right, I did.
You know why?
Because you're one
of the few people I know
that can handle this.
If I'm wrong about that,
please tell me now.
So Red Flag has someone
in my unit on the take.
Maybe all of 'em.
What if someone intercepted
the tip on the witness.
No, no one...
No one intercepted it,
all right?
No one could have known.
Let me tell you something.
The Red Flag are like
the root of a tree in that town.
They're connected to everyone
and everything.
Cops, judges, lawyers.
Hell, even the damn doctors
at Metro General
fudge medical reports
for gunshot wounds
to avoid local law
from asking questions.
You're in the big time now.
Heck, I get it.
It's a shit assignment.
I sent you there to do
what has to be done.
You sent me here because I got
nothin' left to lose, isn't it?
Nothin' to lose
makes 'em dangerous.
You know that.
That poison these scumbags
are slingin' on the streets,
it's the same shit
that took your brother's life.
And capitalists
and homegrown thugs
are getting rich off it.
Hell, Glenn Gargos is like
a goddamn politician now
more than he is a gangster.
You good with that?
I didn't think so.
Tell me something about Gargos.
Just give me something
I can use, all right?
The way he operates,
oh, he's smart.
Not just street smart.
He's always a step ahead.
He's like a predator.
You never see him coming.
So once he puts a price out
on your head,
there's no place on earth
you can run to
where he won't be able
to find you.
Well, why hasn't he
been brought down?
JACK: (ON PHONE)
Why do you think?
This organization is growing
by the day.
Recruit those kids
off the streets.
They drop cash,
everyone benefits.
Good for the fucking local
economy, for Christ's sake.
Des, you still there?
Yeah, Jack, I'm still here.
What are you thinkin'?
Thinkin' I never should have
left Oakland.
JACK: (ON PHONE)
Hey, Des, don't--
Hang up.
(KNOCKING)
Hello.
Hi.
Uh, what's your name?
Millie.
Millie, that is a very
pretty name.
LAURA:
Millie, who is it?
Uh, what are you doing here?
How do you know where I live?
I am a cop, remember.
Hey, why don't you go
finish your homework?
I already finished it.
Okay, why don't you go
into our room
and draw me a picture, okay?
While I talk to the policeman.
-MILLIE: Okay.
-Okay.
Do you wanna come inside?
Thank you.
Sure.
She's beautiful.
Thanks.
Yeah. Uh, how old?
Uh, sh-- she just turned nine.
Just, uh, can I get you a coffee
or...
Oh, no, I'm not here
for a social visit.
That was cool what you
did earlier today.
Buying Olaf lunch.
He's-- he's a good guy.
He's just had a bad run, like--
like most of us.
Yeah. Uh, look, I-- I don't know
how-- how to tell you,
but your brother Jonah is, um...
Oh, my God.
No, he, um...
He tried to kill me today.
(CHUCKLES)
No.
-Yeah.
-No.
Um...
No, that can't be right.
Did you have any idea
he was running with Red Flag?
LAURA:
What?
I mean, my brother,
he's got his problems, yeah?
But he's-- he's not in a gang.
I mean,
he wouldn't hurt anybody.
Look, Laura, I-- I...
Sorry, but I got several
witnesses that say otherwise.
I recognized his face
from the diner
the moment I saw him.
Your contact information
was on his arrest record,
so I just...
...wanted you to know.
He's not getting out, is he?
That I don't know.
It's not my department,
but he's got a laundry list
of charges against him.
So if you have a lawyer,
now's the time.
Uh, I got a--
I got a card here.
It's an old one, but the cell's
still the same, so...
I don't know.
If you need anything,
don't hesitate to call.
Thanks.
Sorry.
(SIGHS)
OLAF:
That cart is mine.
It is mine. I found it.
No, no, no, no, no, dude,
I paid $2.
OLAF:
I know you know a dude.
HOMELESS MAN:
No, no, no, I know the dude.
-OLAF: You know a dude.
-HOMELESS MAN: And I paid--
and you know the dude.
But I paid the dude $2,
and he gave me all of that,
-and I paid him.
-OLAF: All right.
Well, guess what?
It didn't cost me nothing.
Hey, you know
who saw me buy this?
You know, get this?
Deborah saw me buy this.
Uh, uh, yeah.
Oh, okay. Le-- let-- just--
We'll-- we'll--
we'll talk later.
-OLAF: We'll-- we'll talk later.
-All right.
Man, you just don't quit,
do you?
Need to ask you a question.
Well, I've already eaten
chicken and noodle,
so maybe tomorrow.
Olaf, cut the shit.
You hear about the shooting
today at the filling station?
Well, everybody right here
heard about that shit.
Big swingin' balls cop
come around.
Gang bangers end up
in the morgue.
Someone would be happy
about that.
(SCOFFS)
Yeah? Well, go find him.
My witness was nearly
intercepted by Red Flag
before we got to him.
(CHUCKLES)
Yeah.
You're startin' to understand
now, ain't you?
You done walked into a minefield
when you came here,
Mr. Policeman.
Someone from my squad leaked it.
Would you happen to know
anything about that?
Any idea who?
Hmm.
DESMOND:
Talk to me.
(SIGHS)
You're lookin' for a rat
in a nest.
But what you fail to recognize
is this whole town
is one big sewer,
and it's filled
with disease-ridden vermin.
You saying my whole squad
has been?
I'm sayin' be careful
who you trust.
All right, nah, nah, nah.
(GLASS CLINKING)
This on the house.
Yeah.
(GRUNTS)
RODRIGUEZ:
That's stupid.
(RODRIGUEZ LAUGHS)
RODRIGUEZ:
Oh, yeah.
We could cut the rent
when it's cold for a long--
Oh, look who showed up.
Sorry, I'm late.
Only by two hours.
No big thing.
What are you drinking?
Yeah, we got beer and beer.
(CHUCKLING)
Have a seat.
(CLEARS THROAT)
(BOTTLE CAP POPS)
(BOTTLE CAP RATTLES)
(GRUNTS)
Long day.
No judgment here, boss.
WILSON:
So, Mitchell, we just
wanna make sure
our stories line up
about today's shooting.
Line up? It was justified.
It don't matter.
Those pigs down at IAG
are always lookin' for a reason
to put us in the ground.
Do you guys do this often?
Meet up and make sure
there's no discrepancies?
Only on special occasions.
And what constitutes
a special occasion?
Well, it's Tuesday, so...
(LAUGHING)
DESMOND:
Right.
Fair enough.
So you gonna tell us
your story, big man?
My story?
Yeah, man.
I mean, we all got a story.
What's yours?
What brings you
to our little slice of hell?
I mean, you must be some kinda
hero if they sent you here
to lead a special unit.
Um, no.
Not even close.
Grew up in Oakland.
Me and my brother Tony
always wanted to be cops, and...
You know, my dad was a cop,
his dad was a cop.
Is that what we wanna hear?
So where's your brother now?
Ah, he's dead.
Sorry, boss.
What happened?
(♪♪♪)
We got a long drive
ahead of us,
so we might as well be friends.
Still don't see why we
gotta leave the city?
Because Red Flags want you dead.
THUG:
Whoa, whoa, whoa.
Time's up, Detective.
Somethin' on your mind,
Detective?
Curious, really.
DESMOND:
About?
RODRIGUEZ:
You.
Hmm.
RODRIGUEZ:
We did a little digging
and shit on you.
You did?
-Yeah.
-You find anything good?
(CHUCKLES)
-No.
-Hmm.
That's what's bugging me,
amigo.
I think you're hiding something.
I think you should go back
to Oakland.
-Oh, you do?
-RODRIGUEZ: Mm-hmm.
And why is that?
Because you're in
over your head,
and we don't want you here.
(CHUCKLES)
You think you're the first cop
to have a problem with me,
Rodriguez?
See, I'm gonna tell you
somethin'.
I do what I do.
And sometimes my colleagues
like me,
and sometimes they don't.
But truth be told,
I don't give a shit.
I really don't.
See, I'm not here
to make friends.
And if you don't start
addressing me as your boss,
then back the fuck up.
I might lose my temper.
(DAVIS CLEARS THROAT)
You wanna tell me
what that was about?
Just handin' out
some friendly advice.
Didn't look so friendly.
Look, I should go.
Thanks for having me over.
-You got a real nice place here.
-(PHONE RINGS)
Davis.
What?
We'll be right there.
-DESMOND: What is it?
-Wilson.
DESMOND:
Come.
(POLICE SIREN YELPING)
(INDISTINCT
POLICE RADIO CHATTER)
(CARS WHIRRING)
(CAR DOORS SHUTTING)
(INDISTINCT
POLICE RADIO CHATTER)
Son of a bitch.
RODRIGUEZ:
Hey! You wanted a war?
You got one, boss.
MILLIE:
Jonah!
Hey, monkey.
Hey, Millie, uh, can you go
wait in the car with Jonah?
-Okay, come on, Jonah.
-LAURA: Okay.
I was really surprised
to get your call.
Yeah, well, the DA
dropped the charges.
Brother caught quite the break.
I don't know what to say.
It's nothin' to say.
Hey, just not everyone
gets a second chance.
So I hope he takes it.
Oh, I will make sure of it.
(CHUCKLES)
I'm really sorry
about what happened.
Yeah.
Yeah, no, good people died.
But, uh, look,
you should get goin'.
It's not safe
out here right now.
Yeah.
Okay.
(SIGHS)
CHINO:
Look who it is, Renz?
Mr. Big Round Boss Policeman.
And we'll dance again.
Believe that.
(CHUCKLES)
-Count on that, Tin Man.
-(MIMICS A POP)
(POLICE SIRENS WAILING
IN DISTANCE)
(♪♪♪)
(GROANING)
WILLIE:
Whoa, whoa!
What the fuck do you want, pig?
DESMOND:
Just here to have a quick word
with your boss.
Well, he's busy.
So unless you got a warrant,
cop, I suggest you take a hike.
Mav, go clean yourself up.
(♪♪♪)
I got it.
Oh, well, I guess, uh,
you must be the, uh, famous
Detective Mitchell
that I've been hearin'
so much shit about.
I guess that makes you
the piece of shit
I'm gonna put behind bars.
Well, look, it's obvious you
got somethin' on your mind.
Why don't you just come out
and say it?
You crossed the line.
You killed one of my own.
(GASPS)
MELINDA:
Bad boy.
Who did he allegedly kill?
Just wanted to come by,
introduce myself.
Listen, you, uh,
you do what you gotta do
and I'll do what I gotta do.
What you gotta do
is pack up your shit.
I'm giving you 24 hours.
You know, you must like
to hear yourself talk.
Heed the warning.
Just out of curiosity,
what happens within 24 hours?
I think you can all figure
that out for yourselves.
-(GASPS)
-Hmm.
Have a great night.
Who was that prick?
Nothing to concern
yourself with, honey.
(SIGHING)
Oh, no, stay back.
Hey.
Not gonna hurt you, all right?
We have to hurry.
If they see me talkin' to you,
they'll kill me.
You're a cop.
I have information.
But I wanna make a deal.
I need full immunity or I walk.
Well, that's a tall order.
What you have better
be worth it.
It is.
And I have the hard evidence
to prove it.
What are we talkin'?
KAYLA:
Sex trafficking.
I have digital files,
photos, videos.
They scout the hottest clubs,
and they take the girls
against their will.
Look, we can't talk
about this right now.
Uh, fuck.
Hey, it's okay. Let's--
No. Uh, meet me tomorrow
at the corner of 5th and Vine.
Okay. Okay, I gotta go.
(CAR DOORS OPEN)
(CAR DOOR SHUTS)
(CHUCKLES)
Sorry, but you're not my type.
Fuck you, I'm every guy's type.
Who are you
and what did Kayla tell you?
I'm the guy who's gonna
bring down your boss.
So the real question is,
who the fuck are you?
Oh.
You wanna spill the beans
on Gargos,
you wanna cut a deal?
You grow a conscience
all of a sudden, huh?
Stay away from Kayla.
Okay, you're gonna get her
killed.
And if you come back here,
you better bring an army.
Heed the warning.
Okay, back the fuck off.
(DOOR SHUTS)
JACK: (ON VOICEMAIL)
Leave your message
after the tone.
-(VOICEMAIL TONE)
-Jack, call me back.
I'm gonna need a fingerprint
analyzed.
(CAR WHIRRING)
(SPITS)
(LAUGHS)
Oh, man, I should file
a restrainin' order against you
for stalkin' my ass.
I know a cop who can file it.
(CHUCKLES)
Listen, about what you
said earlier,
what'd you mean by that?
(SIGHS)
You look like shit.
Bad day.
Hmm.
See this card right here?
DESMOND:
Union Construction.
-OLAF: Mm-hmm.
-DESMOND: Mm-hmm.
That's where I used to work.
Motherfucker's a billion-dollar
corporation now.
Started from the ground up.
Now they buyin'
all the properties all around
the North Valley.
Out with the old and
in with the new, as they say.
Yeah, that's happenin'
everywhere.
What's your point?
Look...
...I've been listenin'
to all these folks
around here bitchin',
and I can guarantee your ass,
if you start doin' some
digging, you'll find some--
(OLAF SIGHS)
How should I say?
Um, questionable,
diverse investments.
What are you tryin' to say,
Olaf?
Spit it out.
I'm sayin' there's some
major shit goin' on,
and these motherfuckers
are plannin'
to tear down Rome
and everyone in it.
-DESMOND: You got proof of that?
-Yeah, the--
The proof is all around you,
dense motherfucker!
All you gotta do is look!
Can you just give me
a straight answer?
Stop talkin' in riddles.
I-- I-- I've given you plenty.
I mean, you a detective.
Detect, motherfucker!
Jesus Christ.
What's the Andrew Jackson's for?
Get a room. Take a shower.
You stink.
(SNIFFS)
Mm.
Watch your ass, mad man.
(SIGHS)
(CAR ENGINE STARTS)
JACK:
Olaf, huh?
(SCOFFS)
Well, I guess I should be
impressed you took my advice
and got to know locals.
But, listen, don't lose focus
on the job at hand here.
I know you like to let
your mind wander.
That, uh, that print you
sent me,
digital scan was shit,
but my techies got a hit.
Her name is...
...Elsa Walker.
And Des, she's DEA.
What the hell
are you talkin' about?
Jack, how do you
not know about this?
Deep-cover ops rarely share
information, you know that.
Listen, this is a slippery
slope, so watch yourself.
Last thing I need is DEA
in my ass.
DESMOND: (ON PHONE)
Okay, yeah. Thanks.
Yeah, you're welcome.
(KNOCKING ON DOOR)
(DOOR OPENS)
DESMOND:
Oh, hey.
LAURA:
Hi, sorry, I know it's late.
I probably should
have just called.
DESMOND:
Yeah, no, uh, yeah, come on in.
Sorry about the place.
It-- it just, uh...
You know, it is
kinda what it is.
Uh, have a seat.
LAURA:
Okay.
DESMOND:
Where's Millie?
Oh, she's--
she's home with Jonah.
Yeah, we got in a really
big fight tonight.
But I saw something in him
that I haven't seen
in a really long time.
-What's that?
-Fear.
-Hmm.
-It's good.
He said he doesn't wanna have
anything to do with Red Flag,
and he's gonna
get a really good job.
Maybe take us out of
this neighborhood one day.
He's lucky to have someone
like you, I mean.
Listen, um...
I-- I just came by because when
I saw you first at the diner,
I just thought you
were like another cop.
Tryin' to give a hard time
to people like me and Jonah,
but, um, that wasn't the case,
and I just--
I wanted to say that I'm sorry.
There's no reason
to say you're sorry.
It's okay.
So, uh, what happened
with the shooting?
Did that hurt your case?
oh, yep, yeah. But, um...
(CHUCKLES)
Without any witnesses,
it's all hearsay, so...
Red Flag are powerful.
Yep.
And how do you, like,
stop people like that?
You find the source, and you
cut the head off the snake.
I knew the risks
when I took the assignment.
Why'd you take it?
See that guy in that photo?
That's-- that's your brother?
-Mm-hmm.
Tony.
Yeah.
(CHUCKLES)
-I see the resemblance.
-Mm-hmm.
(CHUCKLES)
He was my best friend.
And, uh, when my mom died,
that was the beginnin'
of the end.
Because my dad did what he--
(SIGHS)
What he could do.
But, God bless him,
it was never gonna be enough.
And, um...
Yeah.
I wasn't Tony's brother
anymore, I was his father.
Sometimes his enemy.
Oh, yeah, well, I--
I can relate to that one.
(CHUCKLES)
And then he fell
into the wrong crowd, and...
Mm-hmm.
He, uh,
self-destructive started to use.
And, you know,
you get the phone call, right?
The one you don't want where
they say, "Hey, we found him.
He's dead in an alley."
Hmm. I'm really sorry.
Thanks.
Yeah, um...
And-- and that day,
uh, was the day that...
...I broke.
I started to disconnect and...
Ye-- yeah, self-medicate,
and I was married.
She did the best she could,
but she deserved more,
and I couldn't give it to her.
So, you fall into darkness.
You fall into this big void.
You just spend all your time
just tryin' to dig yourself
out of a hole.
So, when you ask me why,
I guess, um...
Like-- I don't know.
Maybe this feels like--
I don't know.
Sorry. (CHUCKLES)
Yeah.
I'm so sorry.
(♪♪♪)
♪ When you open your eyes ♪
♪ Tell me all you can see ♪
♪ Things aren't here ♪
♪ As you want them
always to be ♪
♪ You just wait for the light ♪
♪ Light ♪
(DISTANT POLICE SIRENS)
What the fuck am I doing here,
Gargos?
This is dangerous,
us meeting like this.
Well, shit happens, sweetheart.
Life's a pickle.
You just gotta make a plan
and roll with it.
I'm gonna ask you one more time.
What am I doing here?
Listen, I learned
a long time ago, honey,
you know, you just don't wanna
trip over the same rock twice.
Go work it out, don't sweat it.
What does this have to do
with me?
Is this about the new guy
in town?
(CHUCKLES)
Hmm?
He's not our problem.
How the fuck was I supposed
to know he was in the rat squad?
Listen, there's always
gonna be problems, all right?
Life is unpredictable.
No!
-(CHOKES)
-Enjoy the ride.
(GAGGING)
(♪♪♪)
WILLIE:
I'll make a display.
Put a hole in her heart.
Chino, Renzo, get this body!
(PHONE RINGING)
(GRUNTS)
Yeah, Mitchell.
When?
Okay, you know what?
Yeah, I'll meet you there.
What is it?
Uh, I gotta go.
Hey, just make sure you lock up
when you leave, okay?
Everything all right?
No.
DESMOND:
Who found her?
We did.
Left her out on the steps
of the precinct,
like an abandoned baby.
Jesus Christ.
Yeah.
Whoever did this,
they were sending a message.
I'm pretty sure
we all know who did it.
Ligature marks, sir, consistent
with death by strangulation.
I count
over four gunshot wounds,
all hit vital organs.
Shooter knew
what he was aimin' for.
Cover her up.
(♪♪♪)
You poked the bear, boss.
What do you wanna do now?
(♪♪♪)
Give me a moment with Cole.
Alone.
Whatever you say.
(CHAIR SCRAPES)
Shut the door.
(DOOR CLOSES)
What's on your mind, boss?
DESMOND:
I don't know who I can trust.
So I'm gonna be bold here.
Was Davis on the take?
Why you askin' me?
(♪♪♪)
Gargos has you all bought.
You, Rodriguez, Davis,
Lewis, and Wilson, I assume.
Hmm?
Yeah, I'll take that as a yes.
What do you want from me?
I wanna help you
out of this, Tom.
And I wanna take down Gargos
and everybody
who's loyal to him.
Yeah, you're out of your mind,
all right?
Gargos.
Gargos is above the law.
Things change.
You'll never get him.
With your help, I might.
What can I do?
I want you to find out
everything you can
on Union Construction,
and don't tell me
you've never heard of 'em.
Okay, I do this...
And no one has to know.
No one.
(SIGHS)
(DOOR OPENS)
(DOOR SHUTS)
(SIGHS)
(DOOR OPENS)
LAURA:
I'm home! Jonah?
Millie?
Mommy!
Hey, baby, what's the matter?
Hi.
You must be Laura.
I'm Willie.
Chill out.
(GASPING)
It's okay.
(GLASS CLINKING)
(SINGS INDISTINCTLY)
(GRUNTS)
Fuck you, man!
(GROANING)
Chief Hager.
Sit down, Detective.
Please, sit down.
I received some information
and it's been authenticated.
What is this?
Bank statements. Wire transfers.
Cash deposits. Zales.
They're all in your name.
No, that...
Chief.
No, I-- I don't know
what these numbers mean.
Look closer.
That's your address.
Oakland, right?
Yeah, that's my account number,
but I don't recognize
any of these transactions.
I know you got
a drinking problem.
problem with authority.
But my friend Jack Keller,
he swore by you.
What-- what do you think
this is?
Chief, you think
these are bribes?
Huh?
-You tell me.
-DESMOND: That's real thin.
These have
obviously been doctored.
CHIEF HAGER:
Hmm.
Who's the source?
Who authorized them?
FIU has been investigating
your unit
for quite some time now.
Jesus Christ.
I'm seeing the same deposits
from the same shell company.
Explain that to me.
What shell company?
Union Construction.
Okay, Chief.
You don't understand.
And I don't have
the whole thing figured out yet.
CHIEF HAGER:
Sure.
And I just need a couple
more days or a couple-- I-- I--
CHIEF HAGER:
You'll have your time
to explain yourself.
Until then,
just call your union rep.
I need your gun.
I need your badge.
(THUD)
You're wrong about this, Chief.
CHIEF HAGER:
I hope I am wrong.
Get your affairs in order, okay?
You will be contacted.
(PHONE RINGING)
I got it!
Des?
What the fuck is goin' on,
Jack?
Uh, just take it easy,
I just heard.
DESMOND: (ON PHONE)
Fuck easy.
Chief just stripped me
of my badge
over some
bullshit bank statement
that mysteriously
showed up on his door step.
I know.
It was planted, and you know it.
JACK: (ON PHONE)
Of course I know it.
But FIU and CCD
have had their hands up
in your unit skirt
for months now.
Whoever's setting you up,
knew that.
Jack, you sent me
here to do a job, okay?
But it seems every move
I make,
I either got you or the Chief
up my ass.
What do you want me to say?
You know, you go in there,
and two days later,
a ball of shit
comes rolling out.
Two dead civilians, dead cops.
What do you expect?
Davis was dirty. She was dirty.
She must have been
the one who leaked.
Oh.
That's-- that's
a moot point now, Des.
-My hands are tied.
-Oh, the hell they are.
You are Deputy Chief.
Somebody somewhere owes
you a favor, Jack.
Isn't that how this all works?
Hey, careful there.
Look, the best thing we could do
is get your ass back to Oakland
while I sort this shit out,
okay?
Wait, that's it?
That's it?
You're just gonna roll me over?
Look, I'll fix this.
But I can't do that
while you burn down
the whole goddamn city.
You know what, Jack?
That sounds like a really
good idea.
-I gotta go.
-JACK: (ON PHONE) Des!
-Des, don't you fuckin'--
-(THUD)
(DOOR BELL CHIMES)
DESMOND:
Is Laura here?
No.
And if you see her,
tell her ass to get down here.
I can't keep covering for her.
(♪♪♪)
Hey, it's Des,
and I'm at the diner.
Look, I don't know
where you are,
but shit is goin' down.
Call me.
(♪♪♪)
(KNOCKING ON DOOR)
(GUN HAMMER CLICKS)
You look like shit.
Yeah, I get that a lot.
Come in.
You're not plannin' on shooting
me with that thing, are you?
Don't tempt me.
What do you got?
Well, considering you're not
technically my boss anymore,
I don't have to tell you shit,
do I?
No, word travels fast.
Had to do some heavy digging,
but lucky for you,
I have a friend
in the FBI field office.
Uh, Union Construction,
they've been under
federal investigation
for three years now.
They're buildin' a case,
but nothing sealed,
no indictments.
But these cats,
they're megacorp.
They got hedge fund investors
all over the country
buying stock in the company.
They got their sights
on Central,
but they just wanna tear it
to the ground,
and they got contractors
ready to build
all sorts of shit.
I'm talkin' restaurants,
bars, condos...
Venture capitalists.
Big fuckin' shock,
they hate the poor.
Yeah, well,
it doesn't stop there.
They're payin' Red Flag
to clean house, Des.
So how deep does this go?
I'm talkin' slavery,
sex trade, drugs.
Uh, I mean,
this is way above both of us.
Right, but you
and the whole crew,
you were funnelin' money
from Gargos.
(SIGHS)
Gargos has offshore accounts.
Dummy corporations, okay?
It would be impossible
to charge him
on any
of his financial dealings.
(THUD)
(GRUNTS)
-(SHOUTS)
-(GUNSHOTS)
(THUD)
(BREATHES HEAVILY)
(GUNSHOTS)
(THUD)
(PANTS)
Shit.
Is that you, Rodriguez?
It's me, baby.
Dale's here, too.
Okay, look, I know you're
both working for Red Flag.
All right? I wanna help ya.
Just hear him out!
Sorry about this, Tom,
but you chose your side.
Hey, just shut up and listen!
All right, I got someone
on the inside.
We can build a case.
If you're talkin' about
that hoe Kayla
or that narc bartender,
I wouldn't count on them
cooperating anymore.
(GASPS)
What have you've been
trying to do, Raven?
Huh? Make friends at the DEA?
Are you sure you really
wanna play it out like this?
'Cause I fuckin' hate you,
Rodriguez.
Oh, I'm sure.
All right, then.
I'm good.
(YELLS)
-(GUNSHOTS)
-(GROANS)
(THUD)
(GROANS)
(YELLS)
(GRUNTING)
(GUNSHOT)
(BREATHES HEAVILY)
(GROANS)
DESMOND:
Cole?
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
You're in over your head,
motherfucker.
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
You okay?
Yeah. She just grazed me.
Bitch never was good
with a splatter gun.
(PHONE RINGING)
Okay. Okay.
(COLE GRUNTS)
All right.
GARGOS:
Talk to me.
Package delivered?
Sorry to disappoint.
Ah, well, Detective Mitchell,
you're a piece of work.
Well, I'll take that
as a compliment.
I'm comin' for you, Gargos.
Hey, brother,
you do what you gotta do.
(GRUNTS)
Get your fucking hands off me!
Get your hands off me!
(GRUNTS)
Huh? Looks like you got
your hands full, friend.
Where do you wanna meet?
GARGOS:
Look, we've already discussed
these things, all right?
Let's just let it roll,
let things happen
the way they're gonna happen,
all right?
You do what you gotta do,
and I'll do what I gotta do.
Adios.
(PHONE THUDDING)
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
He's got a friend of mine.
How good are you with a gun?
I've been shooting
since I was nine.
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
Clean yourself up.
Great. Just great.
(♪♪♪)
DESMOND:
Whatever you do, find the kid.
you ready?
Yeah, I'm ready.
(GUN COCKS)
(♪♪♪)
GARGOS:
Oh, Jesus.
You know, man, you really know
how to rock the boat.
Where's the girl?
The girl? Don't worry
about the girl, brother.
The girl's all right.
You're really gonna make her
an orphan?
Are you that fucking bent?
GARGOS:
Don't worry about the girl.
It's all good.
You know, you got a lot of,
I don't know,
worms in your head.
Maybe you should, like,
take a holiday or somethin'.
I'm not gonna ask you again.
Where's the girl?
Listen, mister, I'm not--
I'm not in the mood
for conversation tonight.
So this is your game?
You work for the suits
at Union Construction,
but you lead
the Red Flag organization,
bunch of low-level street thugs
who knock over liquor stores,
round up young women
as sex slaves.
That it?
(CHUCKLES)
I mean, why do you wanna,
you know, push the envelope
with this thing?
(GUNS COCKING)
How's this?
Listen, you know,
I kinda like you.
You'll get over it.
Like I said, mister,
don't push the envelope.
Don't do it, man,
they'll kill us.
Shut up!
They'll kill us all!
I said shut up!
(JONAH GROANS)
(GRUNTS)
(GUNSHOTS)
(JONAH GRUNTS)
Oh, God, Millie.
(JONAH GROANS)
(THUD)
(GUNSHOTS)
(GUN COCKS)
(LAURA GRUNTING)
(LAURA MUMBLING)
(GUNSHOTS)
GARGOS:
Don't move.
Fuckin' traitor!
(GUNSHOT)
(♪♪♪)
(MILLIE WHIMPERING)
Monkey, are you okay?
Get the kid, I'll cover you.
(GUNSHOTS)
(THUDS)
(MELINDA GRUNTS)
JONAH:
They didn't do anything to you,
right?
Okay, all right.
I'll just put you in here. Okay?
Don't fuckin' move.
Turn around. Don't move.
JONAH:
Please.
She's just a little girl.
Shut the fuck up.
(GUNSHOTS)
LAURA:
Don't you touch me!
Get your hands off me!
(LAURA PANTING)
Drop it!
Okay, okay, okay, okay, okay.
Slowly, slowly.
-COLE: Put it on the ground.
-Okay, okay.
Here we go.
-COLE: Now, stand up.
-MELINDA: Okay.
-Okay.
-Stand Up.
Okay. Okay.
(YELLING, GRUNTING)
(THUD)
You know, this can all end
peacefully, it's you're call.
DESMOND:
You know, you're not
gettin' out of here.
Let's just cut the shit.
You know, you want her,
you can take her.
But you're gonna have to roll
through me first.
You gotta do the right thing.
So, I guess you can do
whatever you gotta do
with my friend here.
Come on. Come on.
(GRUNTING)
(GROANS)
(YELLING)
(GRUNTING)
(PANTING)
(GUNSHOT)
(GASPS)
(THUD)
(CLATTER)
(DESMOND GROANS)
(GRUNTING)
(GUNSHOT)
(GUN HAMMER CLICKS)
Mister, do you think it's, uh,
accident that you're standing
here right now?
Well, hey, you should have
counted your bullets.
(GUNSHOT)
(THUD)
DESMOND:
Go.
Go see Millie.
(YELPS)
(PANTS)
Oh, Millie.
-Millie.
-MILLIE: Mom!
(COLE SIGHS)
LAURA:
Are you okay?
(INDISTINCT SPEECH)
(SOBS)
-Okay. You good?
-Let's go. Let's go. Let's go.
Come on.
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
Where's the kid?
(TAKING DEEP BREATHS)
(♪♪♪)
(PHONE RINGING)
Mitchell,
where the fuck are you?
I have a question for you, Jack.
I'm askin' the questions.
Where the hell are you?
Do you know where the word
"pawn" is derived from?
It's an old French word.
Yeah, interestingly enough,
it comes from medieval times
where they referred to pawns
as foot soldiers.
What the fuck
are you talking about?
That's all that was to you,
wasn't I, Jack?
Just the foot soldier,
a fuckin' pawn.
You know, I thought it was Davis
who sold out those witnesses,
those two kids
who ended up dead.
I thought it was either
Gargos or fuckin' Rodriguez
who forged those bank
statements to set me up.
But it was you.
Mitchell, what the fuck
are you talking about?
Was it the money
Union Construction
was payin' you?
You wanna retire early on
some golf course, Jack,
set up for life?
You set up a DEA agent,
and you got her killed.
And you used a personal
tragedy of mine.
My brother's death.
(SIGHS)
Let me tell you something, Des.
Sometimes it's better to embrace
a disease than fight one.
Make friends with misery
instead of enduring it.
Do you understand?
Yeah, Jack. I certainly do.
(THUD)
FBI AGENT:
Deputy Chief Jack Keller.
What the fuck is this?
FBI.
Put your hands behind your back.
Okay.
(JACK GROANS)
FBI AGENT:
Hands behind your back.
Okay, okay.
(HANDCUFFS CLINK)
Fuck you, Des.
(SIGHS)
(DOOR OPENS)
You all right?
Yeah.
How you feelin'?
Like, I got my ass kicked.
Thanks to you.
Sorry about that.
Well, you sure are the talk
around town right now.
But don't think you
changed anything.
The bigger fish gonna do
what they gonna do.
Yeah, I know.
But the DEA and the Feds,
they're up for blood now,
So they'll get theirs.
Just a matter of time.
Yeah?
Mm-hmm. Little bit at a time.
(SCOFFS)
So, uh--
(GROANS)
What'd you drag me
down here for?
DESMOND:
Take 'em.
(♪♪♪)
Place is yours.
Rent's paid for the next
couple months.
I'm sure you can figure
somethin' out after that.
Hmm?
I...
-DESMOND: Hey.
-♪ Hey you, my friend ♪
DESMOND:
Take care of yourself, Olaf.
♪ Can you even remember me ♪
You do the same.
♪ Well, I can see ♪
♪ Many things
are different now ♪
♪ So what about you ♪
♪ What can you tell me
about yourself ♪
(CHUCKLES)
Crazy-ass fool.
♪ I left behind ♪
♪ My childhood, my innocence ♪
♪ My life, my pride ♪
♪ Never thought
I'd really miss ♪
♪ The simple things ♪
Here we go.
-Hey.
DESMOND:
You ready?
Yeah.
-How about you?
-Yeah.
Bye, monkey. Be safe.
I'll see you soon.
Go ahead. Pop in the back.
You gonna be okay?
Yeah. I think so.
Maybe for the first time.
Good.
I'll call you when we
get there, okay?
♪ I left behind ♪
JONAH:
I'll see you.
-I love you.
♪ My life, my pride ♪
♪ I never thought
I'd really miss ♪
♪ The simple things ♪
♪ And I just want to find my way
back home ♪
♪ My way back home ♪
♪ Ooh, ooh, yeah ♪
I'm still not so sure
about this.
It's not too late
to change your mind.
No.
I think a new start is exactly
what we need.
Me, too.
♪ Ooh, ooh, yeah, yeah, yeah ♪
♪ Living like a real stranger ♪
♪ Yeah, yeah, yeah ♪
♪ Lookin' for a real danger ♪
♪ Yeah, I know ♪
♪ Everything is changing, yeah ♪
(♪♪♪)
♪ This is all mine ♪
♪ For far too long ♪
♪ I've been in this game ♪
♪ Look around you ♪
♪ These curves
will tell my name ♪
♪ You cannot touch me,
you'll never get me ♪
♪ Don't you understand ♪
♪ You were not build for this ♪
♪ I always win at the end ♪
♪ Told you once,
not gonna tell you twice ♪
♪ This place is mine,
I'm always gonna prize ♪
♪ I'm standing firm
in this ground ♪
♪ And I own the crown ♪
♪ This is my house,
these are my rules ♪
♪ This is all mine ♪
♪ I built this empire ♪
♪ I'm never gonna tear it ♪
(INDISTINCT LYRICS)
♪ I built this empire ♪
♪ Everything you see ♪
♪ I'm the one, I'm in control ♪
♪ This is all me ♪
♪ This is all mine ♪
♪ For far too long ♪
♪ I've been in this game ♪
♪ Look around you ♪
♪ These curves
will tell my name ♪
♪ You cannot touch me ♪
♪ You'll never get me ♪
♪ Don't you understand ♪
♪ I always win at the end ♪
♪ I built this empire ♪
♪ I built all this ♪
(INDISTINCT LYRICS)
♪ I built this empire ♪
♪ Everything you see ♪
♪ I'm the one in control,
this is all me ♪
♪ This is all mine ♪
(♪♪♪)
♪ Oh ♪
♪ Yeah, oh ♪
♪ Ah, oh ♪
♪ You see me alone and I ♪
♪ I want you, the love inside ♪
♪ I don't cry anymore ♪
♪ I take you, I taste you,
I leave you in paradise ♪
♪ I want you as an alibi ♪
♪ I focus only on your eyes ♪
♪ I want you, can't even lie ♪
♪ Don't tell me lies,
you're only mine ♪
♪ Na, na, na, na, na, na, na,
baby ♪
♪ Ah, baby ♪
♪ I'm crazy, fallin' again ♪
♪ Can you blame me ♪
♪ I've got my heart
in your hands ♪
♪ And I want you ♪
♪ Yeah, I want you to prove ♪
♪ Your desire ♪
♪ Can't take no more ♪
♪ I can't take no more ♪
♪ And don't let go ♪
♪ Na, na, na, na, na, na, na,
na, na ♪
♪ Yeah, I'm crazy ♪
♪ Na, na, na, na, na, na, na,
na, na, na, na, na ♪
na, na ♪
♪ Won't you love me right ♪
♪ Won't you hold me tight ♪
♪ Na, na, na, na, na, na, na,
na, na ♪
♪ Don't let go ♪
♪ Na, na, na, na, na, na, na,
na, na ♪
♪ Yeah, I'm crazy ♪
♪ Na, na, na, na, na, na, na,
na, na ♪
♪ Na, na, na ♪
(♪♪♪)